Guide to the Ralph I. Gifford Photographs circa 1910s - 1947
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
- Numbered Series, circa 1935 - 1947; Series IV; 675 prints, 496 film negatives, 5 nitrate negatives, and 4 glass negatives
  - The Moat, State Penitentiary; vertical view, 0773; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Washington from Big Lake, 0774
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 8 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Ochoco Homestead, between Prineville and Mitchell, 0775; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Ochoco Homestead, between Prineville and Mitchell, 0776; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Little white schoolhouse on the Imnaha, 0777; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Little white schoolhouse on the Imnaha, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    View similar to image 0777.
  - Eastern Oregon landscape near Prairie City, 1944; 0778
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 1 oversize print and 1 oversize hand-colored print (Box 73, 74)
  - Sleepy Hollow on the Imnaha, 0779
    Postcard (PC) #180; no. 3 paper; 5 counts overall then 3 more to foreground covering all rest then 5 or 6 more making 10 counts for sky; F11 stop.
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 5 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Rail fence and road near Elgin, Oregon, 0780; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    Cut out streak across top; 5 counts on bottom 4 more on clouds; no 3 paper
  - Ma, Pa and Ferdinand (cattle), Wallowa Valley, Oregon, 0781; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    11 or 12 counts foreground 18 clouds; F2 Kodabromide
  - Valley of the Imnaha, 0782; 4x5 negative and oversize print (Box 8, 73)
  - Todd Lake and Mt. Bachelor, 0783; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Evening horizon at Three Sisters, 0784; 4x5 negative and oversize print (Box 8, 73)
  - Pleasant Valley near Mitchell, Oregon, 0785
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 2 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - High Horizon, Wallowa Lake Basin, 0787; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Morning reflections, Moccasin Lake, 0788
    - 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
    - 3 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Glacier Lake, the Wallowas, 0789; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Sunrise on Eagle Cap, the Wallowas, 0790; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Pack string silhouette, 0791; 4x5 negative and mounted oversize print (Box 8, 74)
  - Wallowa Lake Basin country, 0792; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Racing the waves, Brookings, Oregon, 0793; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Fishing in Big Lake, Oregon; Mt. Washington in background, 0794; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    F2 paper 6 counts
  - Loading a mule deer in Imnaha country, 0795; 3 prints (Box 3)
    3 counts F8 stop F2 paper
  - Seven Devils Country from Oregon side of Snake River Canyon, 0796
    5 counts F8 stop F2 paper
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 5 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Packing out a mule deer from the Snake River country, 0797 (Box 3)
  - A cattle man surveys his range on the breaks of the Imnaha, 0798
    5 counts
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 4 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - On Barton Trail to Snake River Canyon, 1944; 0799; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    4 counts
  - Cattle ranch on the Imnaha, 0800; 2 prints (Box 3)
    Similar to State Highway Commission photograph 2228 (Series V).
  - Colvins' Ranch on the Imnaha, 0801; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    Stop 8; F2 paper; 3 counts
  - Colvins' Ranch on the Imnaha, 0802; 2 prints (Box 3)
    3 counts; F2 paper; F8 stop
  - On Barton Trail to Snake River; Colvin Ranch in distance, 0803; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    F8 stop; 5 counts all over; F2 paper; 2 or 3 extra on lower corner
  - Barton Trail thru timber, 0804; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    7 to 8 counts; F2 paper; F8 stop
  - Verne Colvin with pack horse and mule deer on edge of Snake River Canyon, October 1944; 0805
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 4 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Verne Colvin with pack horse and mule deer on edge of Snake River Canyon, October 1944; 0806; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    3 counts; F8
  - Gifford and deer, Snake River country (personal), 0807; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Snake River Canyon from south of Barton Point, 0808; print and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 3, 8)
  - Snake River Canyon and horseman from near Barton Point looking north, 0809; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Horseman on cliff above Snake River Canyon, 0810; 4x5 negative and oversize print (Box 8, 73)
  - Gifford on edge of Snake River Canyon; Seven Devils in distance (personal), 0811; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    F2 paper; F8 stop; 3 counts
  - Sleepy Hollow, on Barton Trail to Snake River Canyon, 0812; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    Similar to image 0770; 4 counts
  - Morgan Ranch on Imnaha from hill above, 0813; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Imnaha Valley; horse and dog, 0814; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Twin pines on the Imnaha, 0815; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Bridge and Morgan Ranch on Imnaha, 0816; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Chief Joseph monument, Wallowa Lake, 0818
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 3 prints (Box 3)
  - Feeder Herefords, Wallowa Valley, 0819; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    F8-10 sec.; Kodabrom F2
  - Pastoral scene, Wallowa Valley; stack of hay fenced off, 0820
    Kodabromide F2; 9 counts; take center of photograph cutting out high foreground
    - 4x5 negative and 3 5x7 copy negatives (Box 8, 61)
    - 3 prints (Box 3)
  - Wallowa Lake, South end, 0821
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 negative (Box 8, 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Eagle Cap and Glacier Lake, Wallowa Co., 0822; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Eagle Cap, Glacier Lake and packstring, Wallowa Co., 0823; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    3 counts on sky first then 5 counts overall then cover and give 2 more to immediate foreground; F8 stop; F2 paper
  - Fish on, inlet to Frazier Lake, 0824; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Fishing, Frazier Lake Outlet, 0825; 5 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - On trail to Frazier Lake, 0826; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Pack horses in the Wallowa Mountains; scene down canyon below Frazier Lake, 0827
    4 counts; F2 paper; F8 stop
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 4 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Leaving floor of valley below Frazier, 0828; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - On trail between Frazier and Moccasin, 0829; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Horses at Moccasin Lake Camp, Wallowas, 0830; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Morning reflections, Moccasin Lake, 0831; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    Postcard (PC) # 181.
  - Thawing out in camp at Moccasin Lake; man and woman warming hands at campfire, 0832; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Snow-bed; Les Simmons and wife shake snow off bedding, 0833; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Frazier Lake from outlet, Granite mountains in background; man fishing near beaver dam, 0834
    Postcard (PC) #176; 4 counts F2 paper; F8 stop.
    - 2 4x5 negatives and 2 5x7 copy negatives (Box 8, 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Immigrant Hill and wheat fields near Pendleton, 0835; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Cascade Highway, Mt. Hood, & Celilo Canal, 0836; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Hood from Big Eddy, The Dalles, Oregon, 0837; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Sentinels of peace; church and poplar trees near New Era, 0838; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Sentinels of peace; church and poplar trees near New Era; view from rear showing grave and tombstone, 0839; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Burnt Ranch near Mitchell, Oregon; entrance to Painted Hills, 0840; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Ice Cream Cone, odd formation in the Painted Hills near Mitchell, Oregon, 0841; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Ice Cream Cone, odd formation in the Painted Hills near Mitchell, Oregon, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Sheep Mountain; fossil beds of the John Day River, 0842; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Sheep Mountain; fossil beds of the John Day River, 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - The Cathedral; formation in the Fossil Bed Country of the John Day, 0843; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Lava Butte, 13 miles south of Bend, Oregon, 0844; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Lava cast of 3 ft. pine log near Bend, Oregon, 0845; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Juniper trees near Bend, Oregon, 0846; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Washington and Big Lake on Santiam Highway, 0847; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Fishing on Big Lake, Oregon; Mt. Washington in background, 0848; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Washington and Big Lake, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - The Three Sisters from Dutchmans Flat on Century Drive, 0849; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Sunset from Lava Butte, 0850; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Sunset from Lava Butte, 2 4x5 negatives
  - "The Ship" rock formation in the Painted Hills of the John Day Valley, Oregon, 0851-0852; 4 prints and 4x5 negatives (Box 3, 8)
  - Deschutes and Crooked Rivers junction, 0853; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Up river from Metolious junction, 0854; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Crater Lake cloud effect, 0855; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    F8 new light 4 counts
  - Wizard Island, Crater Lake, and old snag, 0856; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Mt. Theilsen from Crater Lake Park entrance, 0857; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    no. 3 paper; 3 counts in foreground; 5 in sky; F8
  - Coast Guard Life boat; aerial shot, 0858; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - The Patriarch; Storm Tree, Cannon Beach, Oregon (PC #155), 0859
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 6 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - South Santiam, Cascadia Park, 0860; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Log pond, South Santiam Highway, 0861; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - A typical lumbering scene with a logging train bringing logs to the mill pond, 0862; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - This Oregon mill pond is crowded with logs ready to be transformed into lumber, 0863; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Hood at blossom time; squaw grass and rhododendrons, 0864; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    Postcard (PC) #163.
  - Mt. Hood and rhododendrons (close up), 0865
    Postcard (PC) #162.
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 7 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Mt. Hood and rhododendrons (close up), 0866
    A 16x20 using first developer took 12 counts foreground with up to 20 counts for mountain; G 3 paper F11 stop
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 9 prints (Box 3, 73)
    - 1 oversize print (Box *)
  - Multnomah Falls, showing one walk way and foot bridge, June 21, 1945; 0867
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 6 prints (Box 3, 74)
  - Multnomah Falls, June 21, 1945; 0868-0869; 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Latourelle Falls (upper part of falls); foot bridge in foreground, 0870; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Cannon Beach from Indian Beach, Ecola Park, 0871; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Latourelle Falls (upper part of falls); foot bridge in foreground, 0872; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Croft lily field, Brookings, Oregon, in morning light, 0873; 4x6 print in booklet and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Croft lily field, Brookings, Oregon, in morning light (vertical shot), 0874; 4x6 print in booklet and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Woman in Croft lily field, Brookings, Oregon, in morning light (vertical shot), 0875; 4x6 print in booklet and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Man in Croft lily field, Brookings, Oregon, in morning light (vertical shot), 0876; 4x6 print in booklet and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Croft lily field, Brookings, Oregon, in evening light (vertical shots), 0877-0878; 4x6 print in booklet and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Croft lily field, Brookings, Oregon, in evening light, 0879; 4x6 print in booklet and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Mt. Hood thru pine trees, 0880-0882; 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Snow Geyser, snowplow, 0883; 5x7 diacetate negative (degraded) (Box 75)
  - Cutting a spar tree for lumber operations is a dangerous occupation. More than 200 feet above the ground, a faller is clinging to the trunk just below the branches preparing to remove the top of the tree, 0884; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - The camera catches the tree top just after it has been sawed free, 0885; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - The spar tree swins to and fro dangerously as the faller clings tenaciously to its top before starting his descent, 0886; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Man climbing spar tree, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Douglas Fir, Coast Range, 0887; 2 prints and 8x10 glass negative (Box 3, 57)
  - Myrtle trees near Brookings, Oregon, Chetco River, 0888; 2 oversize prints and 4x5 negative (Box 8, 73)
  - Myrtle trees, mouth of Chetco River, 0889; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    F11 stop; F2 paper 4 1/2 counts for tree; 7 1/2 counts for rest
  - Drive thru Myrtle trees, mouth the Chetco River, 1939; 0890
    F3 paper; 3 1/2 counts; 3 more to top and 3 more to bottom; postcard (PC) #164
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 8 prints (Box 3, 73)
      One print on display in Archives and Maps Reference Room.
  - Close up of myrtle trees on drive thru myrtles, mouth of Chetco River, 0891; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    5 or 6 counts over all then give 4 or 5 more to lower left hand corner; F2 paper; F8 stop
  - Oregon State Capital building, 0892; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #151
  - Oregon State Capital, 0893; 5x7 negative and oversize mounted print (Box 61, 73)
  - Stone sculpture, "Valiant Men Have Thrust Our Frontiers to the Setting Sun," Oregon State Capital building, 0894
    Postcard (PC) #178.
    - 5x7 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 61)
    - 2 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Western Sunset, Oregon coast at Bandon, 0895
    Postcard (PC) #153.
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 4 prints and 1 oversize print (Box 3, *)
  - Western sunset on Oregon coast, 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Bandon Gorse in bloom, 0896; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Albert Morgan on horse, 0897; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Columbia River Gorge from Punch Bowl, Columbia Gorge Hotel, 0898; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - South Falls, rustic bridge, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0899; 1 print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 3, 8)
    Postcard (PC) #112.
  - South Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0900
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 5 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Jane Fitzsimmons on a Sea of Sand; sun on horizon, 0901; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Jane Fitzsimmons walking on sand dunes, Oregon coast; footprints, 0902; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Jane Fitzsimmons standing on sand dunes, Oregon coast, 0903; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Jane Fitzsimmons and man walking on dunes, unnumbered 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Oregon State Capital building, 0904; print and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
  - Wave Patterns, Boiler Bay, Oregon, 0905; 9 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    G3 7 sec. all; F11 3 sec. top postcard negative
  - Storm Clouds, Boiler Bay, Oregon, 0906; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Boiler Bay, 9 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Seascape at Bandon, Oregon, 0907; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Seascape, 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Magnolia tree and Oregon State Capital Building, 0908; 6 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #165.
  - Flowering dunes, 0909; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Magnolia blossoms and Oregon State Capital Building, 0910; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #107.
  - North Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0911; 6 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #91; 2 sec F#2.
  - North Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0912; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #96.
  - Natures Handiwork; A Trail Vista, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0913; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #101.
  - On the North Fork, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0914; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #102.
  - Lower South Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0915; 4x5 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
  - South Falls, Silver Creek; lots of water, 0916; 2 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #93.
  - Lower South Falls trail, Silver Creek, 0917; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
  - Middle North Falls, Silver Creek, 0918; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #100
  - Mt. Hood as seen just above the town of Hood River, looking east, 0919; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Hood River flows down in the foreground into the Columbia River, Oregon.
  - Spring in the Hood River Valley, Oregon; pear blossoms, 0920; 4 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
  - Multnomah Falls, Columbia River Highway, Oregon, 0921; 5 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #160.
  - Multnomah Falls, Columbia River Highway, Oregon, 0922; 3 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #159.
  - Multnomah Falls, Columbia River Highway, Oregon, 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Ledger Card negative, 0923; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Gifford on John Day, 0924; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Sherwood, Oregon, High School Band, 0925; 4x5 negative and 2 8x10 negatives (Box 8, 69)
  - Portraits of Ralph I. Gifford taken by Nels Tinning, 0926; 4 4x5 negatives, 4 5x7 negatives, and 1 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
    Includes copy negative of Gifford in World War I Navy uniform.
  - Boats, Depoe Bay, Oregon, 0927; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Silver Creek Lodge dining room, Silver Creek, Oregon, 0928; 4 5x7 negatives (Box 61)
    Postcard (PC) #168.
  - Yaquina Head Lighthouse, 0930; 5 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
    Postcard (PC) #161.
  - Mt. Hood horseback riders, 0931; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    3 counts foreground; 6 counts mountain; F11 stop; F2 paper
  - Multnomah Falls (similar to 0922), 0932; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - One of the waterfalls at Silver Creek State Park, 0933; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 61)
  - Multnomah Falls, 0934; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    Similar to image 0921.
  - Close up of statue on top of the Oregon State Capital building, Magnolin time, 0935; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Circuit Rider statue in front of the Oregon State Capital Building, 0936; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Liberty Street, Salem, Oregon, 0937; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    10 counts F11-F2 paper; 13 counts on sky
  - Fisherman cabin under bridge, 0938; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    8 counts F2 paper; F11 stop; little extra for foreground
  - Country highway, 0939; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 61)
    8 counts F11 stop; F2 paper
  - Aqualea at Harris Park, Brookings, Oregon, 0940; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    9 counts F2; F11 stop
  - Hood River; Mt. Hood in distance, 0941; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    3 counts F2; F11 stop
  - Hood River with Mt. Hood in distance, 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Wallow Lake, Oregon, 0942
    The last photograph made by Ralph Gifford; postcard (PC) #185; F11 stop; F3 paper; 5 counts develope 60 counts.
    - 6 prints (Box 3)
    - 4x5 negative and 5x7 copy negative (Box 8, 61)
  - Lazy T. Ranch, Chuck Arnold, 0943; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 3, 8)
    3 1/2 counts; F11; F3 paper
  - Ralph Gifford taking pictures of a girl on a hillside at the coast, 0944; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Eagle Cap and Glacier Lake, 10,000 ft., 0946; 5x7 copy negative (Box 61)
    Postcard (PC) #186.
  - Wallowa Lake, 0947; oversize mounted print (Box 73)
    One of Ralph Gifford's last photographs of people.
  - Cutting clover in Wallowa Valley, 0951; oversize mounted print (Box 73)
  - Cutting clover in Wallowa Valley; cloudy, 0952; oversize mounted print. (Box 73)
    Mounted with image 0709 mounted on the back.
- Highway Commission Photographs, 1936-1946; Series V; 26 prints and 1 negative
  Series V consists of photographs made for the Oregon State Highway Commission by Gifford. Several of the photographs may have been made by Cecil V. Ager of LaGrande, Oregon. The images depict views of the Oregon Coast, Wallowa Mountains, Rogue River, Columbia Gorge, Imnaha Canyon, highways and bridges, and strawberry pickers. Similar views of many of the images are part of Series IV.
  - Fishing at mouth of Rogue River, Oregon Coast Highway, 282 (Box 3)
  - Horseback riders in Wallowa primitive area, 323; 2 prints (Box 3)
    Also numbered 1067.
  - Bridge (Highway 101?) over river on coast, 386 (Box 3)
  - Mussel Reef, Oregon coast, 419-420 (Box 3)
  - Mussel Reef near Marshfield and North Bend, Oregon coast, 422 (Box 3)
  - Bandon Beach on the Oregon coast, 432 (Box 3)
    Includes Face Rock.
  - Columbia River Gorge with Vista House in distance, G-402; 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Horseback riders in Wallowa primitive area, 1067 1/2 (Box 3)
  - Highway merge viaduct, 2104 (Box 3)
  - Imnaha Canyon, 2228; 2 prints (Box 3)
    The Imnaha River of northeastern Oregon, in flowing to the Snake River has cut a deep canyon which takes its name from the river responsible for its creation. The Imnaha Canyon is a part of the Wallowa Wonderland which attracts vacationists to regions of unusual scenic allure and unlimited recreational resources.
  - Woman sorting strawberries in baskets, A-463; 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Pickers and truck near strawberry field, A-464; 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Two girls picking strawberries, A-465 (Box 3)
  - Pickers in large strawberry field, A-467; 3 prints (Box 3)
  - Pickers in large strawberry field, A-468; 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Pickers in large strawberry field, A-470 (Box 3)
  - Pickers in large strawberry field, A-471; 2 prints (Box 3)
  - Woman in lava tube, A-503; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    Similar to image 0754 (Series IV).
- Postcard Photographs, circa 1935-1945; Series VI; 58 prints and 57 negatives
  Series VI consists of postcard prints of Oregon scenes produced by Gifford for sale. The series includes primarily postcard prints and 5x7 copy negatives; several larger prints without captions are also included. The images depict waterfalls and other features at Silver Falls State Park; the Wallowa Mountains and Wallowa Valley; the Oregon Capitol building; and the Crooked River Gorge. Other postcards prints are part of Series V.
  - South Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #90; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 63)
    1 1/2 sec.
  - Picnic Area, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #92; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 63)
    2 sec?
  - Middle Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #94; 3 prints, 2 5x7 film positives, and 5 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 63)
    (2 sec?); prints include 2 images of Middle Falls and 1 image of a different waterfall
  - Picnic Area, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #95; print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 63)
    1 sec
  - South Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon; bridge in foreground, PC #97; 7 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 63)
  - Picnic Area, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #98; 1 print and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 63)
  - Double Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #99; 2 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 63)
    2 sec
  - Lower South Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #103; 4 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 63)
    2 1/2 sec
  - Twin Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #105 (Box 3)
  - Log Cabin, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #106; 2 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 63)
    1 1/2 sec [minus]
  - South Falls, Silver Creek, Oregon (long shot), PC #108; 5 prints and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 63)
    1 1/2 sec
  - Lower South Falls Trail, Silver Creek, Oregon, PC #110; print and 2 5x7 negatives (Box 3, 63)
  - The Circuit Rider, Capitol Grounds, Salem, Oregon, PC #111; 2 prints and 5x7 negative (Box 3, 63)
  - Silver Creek Lodge, Oregon, PC #166; 5x7 negative (Box 63)
    4 sec; sent to Kyle Smith in Tacoma, Washington, on June 20, 1951.
  - Snake River Canyon, Oregon, PC #169; 5x7 copy negative (Box 63)
  - Silver Falls Lodge - Oregon - In Winter, PC #169; 5x7 copy negative (Box 63)
  - Winter - Silver Creek - Silver Falls Park, Oregon, PC #170
    - 5x7 copy negative (Box 63)
    - 2 prints (Box 3, 73)
  - Winter - Silver Creek - Silver Falls Park, Oregon, PC #171; postcard print and 5x7 copy negative (Box 3, 63)